This presentation introduces DAL Toolbox, a comprehensive open-source library
designed to make data analytics workflows more modular, transparent, and
reproducible. It was developed through collaboration between CEFET/RJ, LNCC and
INRIA, reflecting an international research effort. The toolbox is openly
available on GitHub, reinforcing its community-driven and academic character. Our
goal here is to explain why DAL Toolbox was created,
what problem it solves, and how it supports systematic experimentation.
The foundation of the toolbox is Experiment Lines, a concept
adapted from Software Product Lines. This framework allows researchers and
practitioners to create families of experiments rather than isolated pipelines.
It addresses the critical challenges of modern data analytics: growing
complexity, need for reproducibility, and integration across diverse tools. By
the end of this talk, you will see how DAL
Toolbox can accelerate research, improve transparency, and support production-level adoption.