The architecture of DAL Toolbox follows a modular design
with clear separation of concerns. Each module—transformation, classification, regression,
clustering, and visualization—serves a distinct purpose. Transformations include operations
like normalization, scaling, and dimensionality reduction. Classification and regression
modules support supervised learning tasks for both categorical and
continuous outputs. Clustering enables unsupervised discovery of structures and
patterns in data. Visualization tools allow users to interpret
results through plots, histograms, scatter plots, and time series
analysis. All modules interoperate seamlessly through a unified API.
This modularity not only simplifies maintenance but also allows
easy extension and integration with external libraries such as Scikit-learn.