The case study illustrates DAL Toolbox in action using
meteorological data from Florida airports. The task was rainfall
prediction, leveraging features like temperature, wind speed, humidity, and
sky coverage. The initial baseline used KNN directly on raw
features without preprocessing. Next, SVM was applied with PCA,
improving dimensionality reduction and robustness. The workflow then evolved
into a Random Forest classifier with normalization. Finally, a
tuned Random Forest was deployed with hyperparameter optimization. Each configuration
built upon the previous one, showing how Experiment Lines
enable systematic workflow evolution. This case demonstrates the reproducibility
and flexibility of DAL Toolbox in real-world data science applications.