DAL Toolbox offers practical functionality across the entire
machine learning pipeline. For transformations, users can perform min-max
scaling, z-score normalization, PCA, and feature selection. For
modeling, the toolbox supports algorithms like KNN, linear regression,
Random Forest, and SVM. Clustering options include K-Means,
providing accessible methods for segmentation tasks. Visualization covers scatter
plots for relationships, histograms for distributions, and line
plots for time series. The unified API ensures that
switching between models or transformations requires minimal code
changes. This makes experimentation both flexible and consistent. Overall,
DAL Toolbox provides a cohesive set of tools
designed to work harmoniously within the Experiment Lines framework.