Several well-known platforms already support machine learning workflows, each
with strengths and weaknesses. WEKA and Orange are excellent
for education, thanks to user-friendly interfaces, but they lack flexibility
for dynamic experiments. RapidMiner and KNIME provide modular graphical
workflows, but their pipelines often sacrifice transparency. Scikit-learn and
Spark MLlib are powerful and widely adopted, yet they lack
systematic support for experimentation. In contrast, DAL Toolbox combines
the strengths of transparency, modularity, and systematic variability. Its
foundation on Experiment Lines allows for reproducible comparisons and structured
exploration. This positions DAL Toolbox as a lightweight yet
powerful alternative, especially for researchers focused on workflow reproducibility.
It strikes a balance between usability, flexibility, and scientific rigor.