The core innovation of DAL Toolbox is the application
of Experiment Lines. Experiment Lines borrow ideas from Software Product
Lines, enabling systematic reuse and controlled variation in workflows.
In practice, this means that each component of a workflow—transformation,
modeling, evaluation—can be optional, interchangeable, or parameterized. This flexibility
allows us to configure entire families of experiments from a
single base structure. It fundamentally changes how data scientists
explore alternatives: instead of building new pipelines from scratch, they
evolve workflows step by step. Variability and optionality ensure
that workflows can adapt to different needs while preserving their
core integrity. The result is more efficient research, reproducibility,
and comparability across experiments. Experiment Lines thus transform workflow design
from a rigid process into a systematic and transparent methodology.