The performance comparison illustrates how each model iteration contributed
to refining the rainfall prediction pipeline. The baseline KNN classifier
was simple and interpretable, but it showed weak predictive accuracy
and struggled with noisy data. The SVM combined with PCA
provided significant improvements by reducing dimensionality and capturing non-linear
relationships, which led to stronger recall values. Random Forest introduced
an ensemble strategy that balanced precision and recall more effectively,
offering a robust middle ground between complexity and performance. Finally,
the tuned Random Forest with optimized hyperparameters achieved the best
overall results, with an F1 score of 0.948. This
result demonstrates that systematic exploration through Experiment Lines is far
superior to isolated, one-off experiments. Each step in the workflow
was not discarded but built upon the knowledge gained from
earlier iterations. This approach showcases how DAL Toolbox promotes reproducibility:
every change, every experiment, is documented and comparable. The
results confirm that Experiment Lines not only improve model accuracy
but also accelerate the research process by structuring how alternatives
are tested. In practice, this methodology supports both academic research
and industry applications where high performance and reproducibility are essential.