Today’s data-driven world involves high-frequency and high-volume streams across
domains like finance, healthcare, urban mobility, and IoT. Traditional approaches
struggle with the scale and heterogeneity of these datasets. Constructing
workflows that are both complete and reproducible remains a major
bottleneck. A key issue lies in integration: data scientists often
juggle multiple libraries with different interfaces and dependencies. This increases
the learning curve and leads to fragmented solutions. Transparency
is another challenge: workflows must be clear and interpretable, not
hidden inside opaque pipelines. Reusability is also essential—components should be
easy to transfer between projects. Finally, workflows must support variability,
allowing researchers to try multiple configurations without starting from scratch.
DAL Toolbox was designed precisely to address these pain points.